Maryam Ashfaq

Software Developer

As an IT graduate with a passion for programming, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and creativity to every project. With a keen eye for detail and a drive for innovation, I strive to develop cutting-edge solutions that push boundaries and exceed expectations.



maryamashfaq1828@gmail.com

+92 324 5250505

Islamabad, Pakistan

maryam037.github.io/MaryamPortfolio/

linkedin.com/in/maryamashfaq5 ir

github.com/maryam037

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Intern

Teresol Pvt. Ltd.

07/2022 - 09/2022

Islamabad

Intern

Inter Services Public Relations , GHQ

06/2024 - 07/2024

Rawalpindi

PROJECTS

Final Year Project

 LitterGo - AI Powered Flutter Mobile Application For Detection And Management Of Litter Dumps using Computer Vision.

To Do List

 Created a simple yet responsive To Do list website, where user can add, delete and clear completed task and if user wants to save them then login/register. Developed using Html, CSS and javascript.

Android Videocalling App

 Created a video calling mobile app using agora.io's video SDK classes, implemented in Java. Offering reliable platform for high-quality video calls for real-time communication and seamless video streaming.

Skateboarding Website

 Using Tailwind CSS, React and Vite created a modern and responsive Skateboarding Blog website for beginners.

Shoes E-commerce Website

 Utilizing Tailwind CSS and MERN developed a visually appealing and responsive e-commerce website for an online shoe store.

Recipe Recommendation System

 Employed content-based filtering through feature extraction and cosine similarity to rank and suggest recipes based on user preferences, GUI developed using the tkinter library in Python.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Bahria University

02/2020 - 06/2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Software Engineering(Exchange semester)

Altinbas University, Istanbul, Turkey

09/2021 - 02/2022

SKILLS



TOOLS

Azure DevOps

PowerBI

Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio

Browserstack

VS code

Android studio

Jupyter Notebook

CERTIFICATES

Data science in python - DataCamp (2021)

LANGUAGES

English
Full Professional Proficiency

Urdu

Full Professional Proficiency

Turkish Elementary Proficiency